Minhajuddin Kasman AR, S.T., PNIIT

Jl. Percetakan Negara XI, Rawasari, Cempaka Putih, Jakarta Pusat, DKI Jakarta 10570 didinkha@gmail.com | 082226732225 | https://mnhjddn.github.io

SUMMARY

Proactive, IT and Data enthusiast who is well organised and skilled at balancing the needs of clients in both personal and professional capacities. Strong work ethic and positive attitude. Highly effective in fast-paced work environments. Accurate, assertive, and adaptable. Experienced in projects and product development with various size of clients such as individual, organizations, companies, start-ups, etc.

SKILL SET

- Data Analytics and Visualization
- Back-End: PHP, Express.js, ASP.NET, etc.
- Front-End: Native JS, JQuery, React.js, etc.
- Database: Ms. SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, etc.
- Full-Stack: LAMP Stack, MERN Stack
- Collab. Tools: Jira, Github, Confluence, Trello
- Project Practices: Waterfall, Agile

- Desktop: C#, Visual Basic, Swing (Java)
- Mobile: Java (Android), C# (Xamarin), etc.
- Design: Photoshop, Adobe XD, Draw.io
- UI/UX: Adobe XD, Figma, InVision, Balsamiq
- Productivity: Ms. Office, Google Docs, etc.
- CI/CD: Github Actions, Bamboo
- •

EDUCATION

- S.T. Information Technology, Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta (GPA: 3.51) Formal
- PNIIT Software Engineering, NIIT Professional Diploma in IT (GPA: 3.93) Non-formal
- M.T.I. Information Technology, University of Indonesia (On-going, Current GPA: 3.34) Formal

EXPERIENCES

1. (2016) Intern, PT. Bukit Asam, Tbk. Unit Pelabuhan Tarahan, Lampung

Single-handedly developed a web application namely SI Mitra PBTA by utilizing native PHP technology. A system for Corporate Social Responsibility program which was meant to replace the company's existing system due to the lack of features such as security, integration, etc.

2. (2016-2018) Part-time and Remote IT Staff, Akademi Ilmu Komputer Ternate

Handled maintenance of Personal Computers in Computer Laboratory including installing software, running diagnostics, etc. and handled the development of the academy's website along with other IT staff.

3. (2019 - 2020) Full-Stack Web Developer, Indonesia Mengajar, Jakarta

Handled various aspects of IT in the organization from managing IT services and infrastructures up to developing the organization's official website with customized content management system and an advanced recruitment which has multiple roles including candidates, assessors, and admins. The system was actively used by more than 7000 users in early 2020.

4. (2020 - Now) Full-Stack Programmer, Bank Rakyat Indonesia, Jakarta

Work as a Full-Stack Programmer within a team that is focused on a business product (Internet Banking Business) and involved in various activities such as planning, analysis, development, and implementation. Proven to be effective in given tasks, delivered quality codes, involved in providing solutions to business and technical needs. Used PHP (Laravel, CI, Lumen), C#, and JavaScript programming language and learned new things such as CI/CD, DevOps tools, collaboration tools, Go Lang., RabbitMQ, etc.